不管那些外星人是谁
Whoever those aliens are,
他们可不是刚到
they haven't just arrived,
他们已经在这待了一段时间了
they've been here for a while.
哈丽特·琼斯 弗莱德尔北区议员
Harriet Jones, MP for Flydale North.
我还以为现在我是首相了
I thought I was Prime Minister now.
多谢各位佩戴身份牌
Thank you all for wearing your ID cards.
辨识尸体时方便多了
They'll help to identify the bodies.
对人类也许是致命的
Deadly to humans, maybe. . .
神秘博士第一季第五集
第三次世界大战
杰琪
Jackie!
想抓外星人吗 那你们可来对了
You want aliens, you've got them.
他们就在唐宁街里
They're inside Downing Street.
跟我来
Come on!
快帮我再伪装起来 快 快
Reinstate my disguise! Hurry up, hurry, hurry!
慢着 有东西没拿出来
Wait! They're still in there
紧急条例 我们需要那些文件
the Emergency Protocols, we need them.
你们怎么才来
Where've you been?
我叫人来救我 还拉响了警报
I called for help, I sounded the alarm. . .
有那么一道光 之类的
there was this... lightning, this kind of,
就是电光那种 然后他们全倒下了
um, electricity, and they all collapsed.
我看他们全死了 -我就说嘛
I think they're all dead. - That's what I'm saying.
是他干的 就是他
He did it! That man there!
我想你们会发现这个首相
I think you'll find the Prime Minister
其实是外星人假扮的
is an alien in disguise.
你们不会相信的是吧 -没错
That's never gonna work, is it? - No.
那好吧
Fair enough.
在这边
Down there!
基于紧急条例授予我的权力
Under the jurisdiction of the Emergency Protocols,
我命令你们处决这个人
I authorise you to execute this man!
这个 好吧 你们看 是这样的
Well, now, yes, you see, er, the thing is...
如果我是你 如果我把某个人
If I was you, if I was gonna execute someone
逼到墙角 好把他杀掉
by backing him up against the wall,
我得给你个小建议
between you and me, little word of advice.
别让他背靠电梯
Don't stand him against the lift.
你好
Hello!
快躲起来
Hide!
我再说一遍 封锁上面几个楼层
I repeat, the upper floors are under quarantine.
你们要严守岗位
You will stay where you are,
之前的命令全部无效
you will disregard all previous instructions,
只能直接听从我的调遣
you will take your orders directly from me.
格林先生 不好意思 但您必须跟我来
Mr Green, sir, sorry, but you've got to come with me.
我们必须疏散整栋大楼
We should evacuate the building.
中士 你读过紧急条例吗
Sergeant, have you, um, read the Emergency Protocols?
没读过 先生 -那就别质疑我
No, sir. - Then don't question me.
封锁首相府 守好一楼
Seal off Number Ten, secure the ground floor,
而且如果博士下楼来了 格杀勿论
and if the Doctor makes it downstairs, shoot on sight!
没长耳朵吗 行动
You heard him, move out!
好戏开始了
Let the sport begin.
这气体交换系统真是熏死我了
I'm getting poisoned by the gas exchange.
我真想光着身子 -你就满足吧
I need to be naked. - You're joice in it.
你的身体非常强壮
Your body is magnificent.
多好玩啊
Oh, such fun.
人类小孩 藏到哪里去啦
Little human children, where are you?
可爱的小人类 来跟我玩嘛
Sweet little human kins, come to me.
让我好好亲你一个
Let me kiss you better.
用我的大绿嘴唇亲亲你
Kiss you with my big green lips.
快去那边看看
Go and check it out!
猎捕对我们有益 能净化我们的血液
It does us good to hunt, it purifies the blood.
我们就把这一层封锁起来
We'll keep this floor quarantined
作为我们最终阶段之前的藏身之所
as our last hiding ground before the final phase.
我的兄弟们 -捕猎愉快么
My brothers. - Happy hunting?
非常愉快
It's wonderful.
你下手越慢 他们的臭味就越浓
The more you prolong it, the more they stink.
浑身大汗 心惊胆战
Sweat and fear!
我能闻到一个老女人的气息
I can smell an old girl.
老气的香水 骨头一捏就碎
Stale perfume and brittle bones.
还有一个少女 全是青春与荷尔蒙味儿
And a ripe youngster, all hormones and adrenalin.
足够新鲜 不会一折就断
Fresh enough to bend before she snaps.
不 冲我来 先吃我
No! Take me first, take me!
快走 跟我来
Out! With me!
你是谁
Who the hell are you?
哈丽特·琼斯 弗莱德尔北区议员
Harriet Jones, MP for Flydale North.
幸会幸会 -彼此彼此
Nice to meet you. - Likewise.
我们得去内阁会议室
We need the Cabinet Rooms.
紧急条例就在那里
The Emergency Protocols are in there.
里面有如何应对外星人的指示
The human instructions for aliens.
哈丽特·琼斯 我喜欢你 -我也是
Harriet Jones, I like you. - I think I like you too.
再前进一步 我的音速起子将会
One more move and my sonic device'll triplicate
把这瓶酒精的可燃性提升三倍
the flammability of this alcohol.
一把火我们全完蛋 退后
Woof, we all go up. So back off.
很好 提问时间到
Right, then, question time.
斯利辛究竟是什么人
Who exactly are the Slitheen?
他们是外星人 -我看出来了 多谢
They're aliens. - Yes, I got that, thanks.
如果你不是人类 那你是谁
Who are you, if not human?
谁不是人类
Who's not human?
他不是人类
He's not human.
他不是人类吗
He's not human?
能不能静一静 -抱歉
Could I have a bit of hush? - Sorry.
那么 你们想怎样
So, what's the plan?
但是他有北方口音啊
But he's got a northern accent.
许多星球都有北方 -我说了 安静点
Lots of planets have a north. - I said hush!
说啊
Come on!
你们在北海里藏了一艘太空飞船
You've got a spaceship hidden in the North Sea.
那飞船还在发射信号
It's transmitting a signal.
你们一路杀到了政府高层
You've murdered your way to the top of government,
目的何在 要入侵吗
what for, invasion?
我们为什么要入侵这个破石块星球
Why would we invade this godforsaken rock?
那斯利辛种族来到这里肯定有所图 是什么
Then something's brought the Slitheen race here. What is it?
什么斯利辛种族 斯利辛不是我们的种族名
The Slitheen race? Slitheen is not our species.
斯利辛是我们的姓氏
Slitheen is our surname.
乔卡萨·菲富奇·帕萨梅戴·斯利辛
Jocrassa Fel Fotch Pasameer-Day Slitheen
为您效劳
at your service.
你们是一家人 -这是家族生意
So you're family? - A family business.
那你们来这肯定有利可图
Then you're out to make a profit.
这破石头星球上能有什么赚头
How can you do that on a godforsaken rock?
抱歉问一句 你那玩意儿
Excuse me. Your device
能做什么来着 "可燃性加三倍"
will do what - "triplicate the flammability"?
是这样的 -你就瞎编吧
That's what I said. - You're making it up.
说得没错
Oh, well. Nice try.
哈丽特 喝点吧 我看你需要壮壮胆
Harriet, have a drink. I think you're gonna need it.
你还是先给你左边那位吧 -抱歉
You pass it to the left first. - Sorry.
多谢 -现在我们就要把你们全杀光
Thanks. - Now we can end this hunt... with a slaughter.
你不觉得我们该逃命吗
Don't you think we should run?
唐宁街的历史可是真精彩啊
Fascinating history, Downing Street.
2000年前这里还是一片沼泽地
2000 years ago, this was marshland.
1730年又被一位小鸡先生占领了
1730, it was occupied by a Mr Chicken.
他是个好人
He was a nice man.
1796年 这里成为了内阁会议室
1796, this was the Cabinet Room.
如果正在开会的内阁面临危险
If the Cabinet in session and in danger,
这些墙将会构成全英国
these are about the formal safest walls
最安全的密室
in the whole of Great Britain.
课程结束
End of lesson.
安装于1991年 3英寸厚的钢板
Installed in 1991. Three inches of steel,
衬在每一道墙里
lining every single wall.
他们别想进来 -那我们怎么出去
They'll never get in. - And how do we get out?
他在里面 我们动他不得
He's safely contained.
把那个房间的通讯切断
Now cut off the communications inside that room,
然后召集全家族
then summon the family!
赶快把这个疯狂的星球彻底毁灭
It's time we finished with this insane planet for good.
唐宁街里仍未有任何消息传出
And there's still no word from inside Downing Street,
但是更多政要接二连三走进首相府
though we are getting even more new arrivals.
那位是皇家空军上校坦南特·詹姆斯
That's Group Captain Tennant James of the RAF,
至于首相为何召见他我们不得而知
though why he's been summoned, we've no idea.
那一位是尤恩·麦卡利斯特
And that's Ewan McAllister,
苏格兰议会副秘书长
Deputy Secretary for the Scottish Parliament.
而下一位更是不同寻常
And this is most unusual -
我得知她是西尔维娅·迪兰
I'm told that is Sylvia Dillane,
北海游船俱乐部主席
chairman of the North Sea Boating Club.
我们完全不知道这些人之间有什么联系
Quite what connects all these people, we have no idea.
上校
Group Captain.
您能来太好了 会议室在楼上
Delighted you could make it. We're meeting upstairs.
这才像话 快去吧
That's the spirit, off you go.
幸会幸会 快过去吧
Good to see you. Come on through.
中士 既然博士已经被消灭了
Ah, Sergeant. Now that the Doctor's been neutralised,
上面楼层禁止任何人进入
the upper levels are out of bounds to everyone.
那他们是谁
Then who are they?
需者方知 中士 别多问
Need to know, Sergeant, need to know.
我需要你保持通信畅通
I want you to liaise with Communications.
代理首相将发表公众演讲
The Acting Prime Minister will be making an public address.
他将对全世界讲话
He will speak to the nations of the world!
麻烦你来这边换一下衣服
If you'd just like to go through and get changed.
沿着走廊一直走
Now, if you'd like to head down to the end of the corridor,
左手边第一个门
it's first on the left.
多谢
Thank you.
还有更猛一点的吗 -不行
Got anything stronger? - No chance.
我可见过你刚喝了几杯就大跳康茄舞
I've seen you and you've had a few the same thing for a Conga!
我们得跟谁说说这事
We've gotta tell someone!
我们能信谁 就我们所知
Who do we trust? For all we know,
他们体内全都藏着个黏兮兮的大怪物
they've all got big bog monsters inside of 'em.
他就是这种人 杰琪
I mean this is what he does, Jacks.
那个什么博士 有他的地方
That Doctor bloke, everywhere he goes,
就有死亡和毁灭 他还把洛斯也卷进去了
death and destruction, and he's got Rose in the middle of it.
那他体内是不是也有个大绿怪物啊
Has he got a great big green thing inside him, then?
说不准还真有
I wouldn't put it past him.
但不管怎样
But like it or not,
只有他知道怎么对付这些怪物
he's the only person who knows how to fight these things!
我还以为我死定了
I thought I was gonna die.
别哭了 好吗
Come on, yeah?
就是要哭 也得是我哭啊
If anyone's gonna cry, it's gonna be me.
你在我的公寓里是安全的 杰琪
Now, you're safe in my flat, Jacks.
没人会来这找你
No-one's gonna look for you here,
尤其是你还这么讨厌我
especially since you hate me so much!
你救了我的命 天呐 真尴尬
You saved my life! God, that's embarrassing!
可不是么
Telling me!
他想害死我
He wanted me dead.
而他还在外面 米奇
And he's still out there, Mickey.
那个警察 那个怪物
That policeman... that thing!
好 给你个任务
Right, you head off.
通知下去 我还有点事情要处理
Inform control I've one or two things that still need doing.
我和泰勒太太还没完
I haven't quite finished with Mrs Tyler yet.
咱们的人都在这儿了吗
Is that all of us?
除了西普·菲富奇 家族里的人都在这儿了
All the family except Sip Fel Fotch.
他发现了自己的猎物
He's found a hunt of his own.
他叫什么名字
What was his name?
谁 -这个人 好像是个秘书什么的
Who? - This one. The, er, secretary, or whatever he was called.
我不知道 我和他说过话
I don't know. I talked to him.
还给他端了一杯咖啡
I brought him a cup of coffee.
我没有问过他的名字
I never asked his name.
对不住了
Sorry.
咱们找到了什么 有什么发现吗
Right, what have we got? Any terminals, anything?
没有 这地方有些年头了
Nope, this place is antique.
我不明白的是 他们杀死首相以后
What I don't get is when they killed the Prime Minister,
为什么不用首相的皮囊呢 -他太瘦了
why didn't they use him as a disguise? - He's too slim.
他们得藏在那些大块头的人里面
They need to fit inside big humans.
可是斯利辛有八英尺高
But the Slitheen are about... eight feet.
他们是怎么把自己塞进去的
How do they squeeze inside?
他们脖子上的那个装置 压缩力场
That's the device round their necks, compression field,
可以把他们变小
literarily shrinks them down a bit.
所以总会排出那些气体
That's why there's all that gas.
气体交换量很大
It's a big exchange.
要是我有压缩力场就好了 我就能变苗条了
Wish I had a compression field. I could fit a size smaller.
抱歉 都出人命了 现在可没工夫开玩笑
Excuse me, people are dead! This is not the time for jokes.
抱歉 作为他的朋友就得慢慢适应这种事
Sorry, You get used to this stuff when you're friends with him.
这种友情可够荒唐的
Well, that's a strange friendship.
哈丽特·琼斯 我以前好像听过这个名字
Harriet Jones. I've heard that name before.
哈丽特·琼斯
Harriet Jones.
你不是什么名人吧
You're not famous for anything, are you?
不是 -我有印象 哈丽特·琼斯
Hardly! - Rings a bell. Harriet Jones?
我一辈子都是个小议员
Lifelong backbencher I'm afraid,
现在也是派不上什么大用场
and a fat lot of use of I am being now.
那些条例太冗长了
The Protocols are redundant.
有个可以求助的名单 可他们都死在楼下了
They list people who could help and they're all dead downstairs.
有没有什么防御代码一类的东西
Hasn't it got, like, defence codes or somethings?
我们不能直接用核弹把他们炸飞吗
Couldn't we just launch a nuclear bomb at them?
你真是个暴力的小姑娘
You're a very violent young woman.
我是认真的 -这儿可没有什么核弹
I'm serious, we could! - There's nothing like that in here.
核弹攻击是需要发射口令的
Nuclear strikes do need a release code,
可是联合国对此一直保密
yes, but it's kept secret by the United Nations.
你再说一遍 -说什么 口令吗
Say that again. - What, about the codes?
把你刚才说的全部再说一遍
Anything, all of it.
没有联合国的特别决议
The British Isles can't gain access to
大不列颠诸岛是无权使用原子武器的
atomic weapons without a Special Resolution from the UN.
说得好像这样就能阻止他们似的
Like that's ever stopped 'em.
就是 看历史就知道 我当时投了反对票
Exactly, given our past record... and I voted against that.
谢谢
Thank you very much.
口令不在政府手里
The codes have been taken off the Government's hand
被交给了联合国 这很重要吗
and given to the UN. Is it important?
任何信息都很重要
Everything's important.
我们要是知道斯利辛家族想干什么就好了
If only we knew what the Slitheen wanted.
我竟然这样正常的叫他们的名字
Listen, I'm saying Slitheen as if it's normal!
可他们究竟想干什么呢
What do they want, though?
他们只是一个家族 所以应该不是入侵
They're just one family, so it's not an invasion.
他们没打算征服地球
They don't want to enslave the world.
如果他们只是为了赚一票
They're out to make money.
或是看上了什么东西 地球上的某种东西
that means they want to use something, something here on earth.
什么资源之类的 -比如什么 黄金么
Some kind of asset. - Like what? gold?
石油 或者水
Oil? Water?
你猜这个很在行嘛
You're very good at this.
谢谢
Thank you.
哈丽特·琼斯 为什么我总觉得很耳熟
Harriet Jones, why do I know that name?
我的电话 -都屏蔽了你怎么还有信号
Oh, that's me. - It's sealed off. How did you get a signal?
他改进了这部超级手机
He zapped it. Super phone.
这样就可以打电话了 你们一定有帮手吧
Then we could phone for help. You must have contacts!
没错 死在楼下了
Dead downstairs, yeah.
是米奇
It's Mickey.
告诉你的蠢货男友 我们现在很忙
Oh, tell your stupid boyfriend we're busy.
好 可是他没你说得那么蠢
Yeah, he's not so stupid after all.
不 不 不只是外星人
No, no, not just alien,
而是彻彻底底的外星人
but like, proper alien,
臭烘烘 湿漉漉的 让人恶心
all stinking and wet and disgusting,
更重要的是 它想杀死我们
and more to the point, it wanted to kill us!
我差一点就死了 -她没事吧
I could have died! - Is she all right though?
不用叫她接电话 你告诉我就好
Don't put her on, just tell me.
里奇吗 什么都别说 先打开你的电脑
Is that Ricky? And don't talk. Just shut up and go to your computer.
我是米奇 开电脑干什么
It's Mickey, and why should I?
傻瓜米奇 接下来的话
Mickey, the idiot, I might just choke
我有点说不出口 但是我需要你的帮助
before I finish this sentence, but... I need you.
联合国特别情报小组
要输入密码
It says "password?"
再说一遍
Say again.
需要输入密码
It's asking for the password.
Buffalo 两个F 一个L
Buffalo. Two Fs, one L.
这是什么网站
So what's that website?
这里有全人类已知的所有秘密
All the secret information known to mankind.
他们在很多年前就知道有外星人了
See, they've known about aliens for years.
只不过我们一直被蒙蔽了双眼
They just kept us in the dark.
米奇 你压根就没开过眼
Mickey, you were born in the dark.
别招惹他 -谢谢
Oh, leave him alone. - Thank you.
还要输入密码 -每次密码都一样
Password again. - Just repeat it, every time.
大本钟 斯利辛人为什么要撞大本钟
Big Ben. Why did the Slitheen go and hit Big Ben?
你说是为了把专家们聚在一起 杀了他们
You said to gather the experts, to kill them.
哪怕放个气象气球也能把这帮专家召集起来
That lot would've gathered for a weather balloon.
完全没必要在伦敦中心搞个紧急降落
You don't need to crash-land in the middle of London.
斯利辛人藏了起来
The Slitheen are hiding,
可他们又偏偏让所有地球人拉响了警报
but then they put the entire planet on red alert.
这是为什么呢
What would they do that for?
你听听她 -至少我尽力了
Oh, listen to her! - At least I'm trying.
抱歉 我有一个问题
I've got a question, if you don't mind.
自从那个男人出现在我们的生活里
But since that man walked into our lives,
先是我在街上遭到了袭击
I've been attacked in the streets,
后来又有一堆不知名的生物出现在我的客厅里
I've had creatures from the pits of hell in my own living room
我的女儿还从地球上消失了
and my daughter disappear off the face of the Earth.
我已经跟你解释过了 -我在跟他说话
I told you what happened. - I'm talking to him!
我见识过你的生活了
Cos I've seen this life of yours,
博士 也许你乐在其中
Doctor, and maybe you get off on it,
或者你觉得这一切精彩绝伦
and maybe you think it's all clever and smart,
可是你告诉我 回答我
but you tell me - just answer me this -
我女儿跟着你安全吗
is my daughter safe?
我很好
I'm fine.
她安全吗
Is she safe? !
你能向我保证 她会一直安全吗
Will she always be safe, can you promise me that?
回答我啊
Well, what's the answer?
我们登录进去了
We're in.
现在 左上角
Now, then. On the left, at the top,
有一个图标 是个同心圆 单击那里
there's a tab, an icon, little concentric circles, click on that.
那是什么 -斯利辛人有一艘飞船
What is it? - The Slitheen have got a spaceship
正在北海里发射信号
in the North Sea transmitting that signal. Now,
安静点儿 我要搞清楚它在传递什么信息
hush, let me work out what it's saying.
他迟早有一天得回答我
He'll have to answer me one day.
安静 -这个信号像是在传递什么信息
Hush! - It's some sort of message.
什么信息 -不知道 一直在重复
What's it say? - Don't know, it's on a loop, keeps repeating.
安静点儿 -不是我
Hush! - That's not me!
你去看看怎么回事
Go and see who that is.
现在是凌晨三点 -那你去告诉他们
It's three o'clock in the morning. - Well, go and tell them that!
信号是发向太空的 这是发给谁的呢
It's beaming out into space. Who's it for?
行了
All right!
泰勒太太
Mrs Tyler.
是他 那家伙追来了 那个斯利辛人
It's him, it's the thing! It's the Slitheen!
他们发现我们了
They've found us!
米奇 我需要那个信号
Mickey, I need that signal.
别管信号了 先想办法出去 妈妈
Never mind the signal, get out! Mum just get out!
我们出不去 那家伙就在门口
We can't, it's by the front door.
天呐
Oh, my God.
它在恢复原形 它想杀了我们
It's unmasking. It's gonna kill us.
一定有办法能够阻止它们
There's got to be some way of stopping them!
你才是这方面的专家 快想想办法
You're supposed to be the expert - think of something!
我在想呢
I'm trying!
我来对付他 杰琪 你快跑
I'll take it on, Jackie. You just run.
别回头 只管跑
Don't look back. Just run.
那是我妈妈
That's my mother.
好了 要想找到它们的弱点
Right! If we're gonna find their weakness,
就先要搞清楚它们是从哪个星球来的
we need to find out where they're from, which planet.
根据它们的原形来判断 我们可以锁定到
So, judging by their basic shape, that narrows it down
附近时空旅行范围内的5000个星球
to five thousand planets within travelling distance.
我们还知道些什么 给点儿提示
What else do we know about them? Information!
他们是绿色的 -把范围再缩小一点
They're green! - Narrows it down.
他们嗅觉发达
Good sense of smell.
范围再小一点 -他们可以闻到肾上腺素
Narrows it down. - They can smell adrenaline.
范围再缩小一点 -还有猪技术
Narrows it down. - Pig technology.
范围再缩小一点
Narrows it down.
泰晤士河里的飞船 气流引擎
Spaceship in the Thames. Slipstream engine.
范围再小一点
Narrows it down.
它要进来了
It's getting in!
它们把捕猎作为一种仪式 -范围再小点
They hunt, like a ritual. - Narrows it down.
等一下 你们注意到没有
Wait, did you notice...?
他们放屁的时候 请原谅我的用词
When they fart, if you'll pardon the word,
闻起来并不像是屁的气味 请原谅
it doesn't just smell like a fart, if you'll pardon the word,
而是其他什么味道 什么呢 就好像
it's something else? What? It's more like, um.
口臭 -没错
Bad breath! - That's it!
是钙腐烂的味道
Calcium decay!
现在范围够小了
That narrows it down!
我们有办法了 妈妈 -来不及了
We're getting there, Mum! - Too late!
磷酸钙 有机钙 活性钙
Calcium phosphate, organic calcium, living calcium,
活性钙构成的生物 还有什么
creatures made out of living calcium. What else?
还有复合起来的姓氏 没错
Hyphenated surname! Yes!
现在范围缩小到一个星球了
That narrows it down to one planet!
拉克西科里科弗拉帕多里斯星
Raxacoricofallapatorius!
好极了 我们可以给他们写封信
Great, we can write 'em a letter
到厨房里去
Get into the kitchen!
天呐 它快要把我们撕碎了
Oh, God, it's going to rip us apart!
压缩力场会使钙弱化
Calcium weakened by the compression field.
还有乙酸 醋
Acetic acid! Vinegar!
就像汉尼拔一样 -就像汉尼拔一样
Just like Hannibal! - Just like Hannibal!
米奇 你那儿有醋吗 -我怎么知道
Mickey, have you got any vinegar? - How should I know?!
那是你家厨房
It's your kitchen!
水槽上面的壁橱里 中间那层
Cupboard by the sink, middle shelf!
你就快说吧 你要什么 -含醋的都行
Oh, give it here. What d'you need? - Anything with vinegar.
酸黄瓜
Gherkins!
还有腌洋葱
Yeah, pickled onion!
腌鸡蛋 -这你也敢亲
Pickled eggs! - You kiss this man?
汉尼拔是怎么回事
Hannibal?
汉尼拔·巴卡用醋溶解砾石穿越了阿尔卑斯山
Hannibal crossed the Alps by dissolving boulders with vinegar.
总算搞定了
Well, there you go, then.
他死了
He's dead.
斯普·菲富奇·帕萨梅戴·斯利辛死了
Sip Fel-Fotch Passameer-Day Slitheen is dead.
我感觉到了
I felt it.
这怎么可能
How could that happen?
一定是靠运气
Somebody must've got lucky.
这大概是这个破星球上的人最后的一点运气了
That's the last piece of luck anyone on this rock will ever have.
女士们先生们
Ladies and gentlemen,
世界诸国
nations of the world.
以及全人类
Humankind.
今夜全世界最优秀的外星事件专家都来到这里
The greatest experts in extraterrestrial events came here tonight.
他们因为一个共同的原因齐聚一堂
They gathered in the common cause.
但我现在要告诉你们的消息十分沉重
But the news I bring you now is grave indeed.
专家们都死了
The experts are dead.
就在我的眼前 被外星人亲手谋杀了
Murdered, right in front of me, by alien hands.
地球的子民们 请听我说
Peoples of the Earth, heed my words.
这些"访客"并非抱着和平的意图前来
These "visitors" do not come in peace.
听听这个
Listen to this!
调查官已搜索了我们头顶上的天空
Our inspectors have searched the sky above our heads,
而他们发现了
and they have found...
大规模杀伤性武器
massive weapons of destruction
可在45秒内部署 -什么
capable of being deployed within 45 seconds. - What?
我们的技术人员能抵挡外星人的探测
Our technicians can baffle the alien probes
但坚持不了多久
but not for long.
我们正面临种族灭绝的厄运
We are facing extinction.
除非我们先下手为强
Unless we strike first!
英国正好处于
The United Kingdom stands
母舰正下方
directly beneath the belly of the mothership.
我请求联合国
I beg of the United Nations,
通过一项紧急决议 给我们接入密码
pass an emergency resolution. Give us the access codes.
对母舰的核心进行一次核打击
A nuclear strike at the heart
是我们活下来的唯一机会
of the beast is our only chance of survival.
因为
Because...
从此刻起
from this moment on,
我要郑重地向各位宣布
it is my solemn duty to inform you,
地球进入战争状态
planet Earth is at war.
他在胡扯
He's making it up!
上面根本没武器 什么威胁都没有
There's no weapon up there, there's no threat.
完全是凭空捏造 -你觉得大家会信他吗
He's just invented it! - Do you think they'll believe him?
你上次就信了
You did last time.
这就是斯利辛大张旗鼓的缘由
That's why the Slitheen went for spectacle.
它们想让全世界陷入恐慌
They want the whole world panicking,
因为你们人类一慌了神 就会不顾一切
cos you lot, you get scared, you lash out.
然后就发送核武器密码
Then release the defence codes.
然后斯利辛就得到核武器了 -但为什么
And the Slitheen go nuclear. - But why?
你们拿到密码发射核弹 但不是指向太空
You get the codes, release the missiles. But not into space,
因为那里什么都没有
'cos there's nothing there.
你们会攻击地球上所有其他国家
You attack every other country on Earth.
然后他们会进行报复性打击
They retaliate, fight back.
第三次世界大战 整个星球都遭受核攻击
World War Three. Whole planet gets nuked.
而我们可以高台看戏
And we can sit through it,
躲在泰晤士河中待机的飞船里安然无恙
safe in our spaceship, waiting in the Thames.
根本没坠毁 只是停泊而已
Not crashed, just parked.
离这里就两分钟车程吧
Barely two minutes away.
但你们会毁灭这个美丽的行星 为什么
But you'll destroy the planet. This beautiful place. What for?
利益 发往宇宙的信号其实是广告
Profit. That's what the signal is, beaming into space, an advert.
绝世大甩卖啊
Sale of the century!
我们把地球先熔成渣 再卖掉
We reduce the Earth to molten slag, then sell it.
一块一块地卖
Piece by piece.
这些有放射性的碎块
Radioactive chunks
可以为廉价的星际航空和货运飞船提供动力
capable of powering every cut-price starliner and budget cargo ship.
外面经济不景气 博士 人们低价买入
There's a recession out there, Doctor. People are buying cheap.
这个大岩块会变成原始燃料
This rock becomes raw fuel.
这可是以50亿人的生命为代价的
At the cost of five billion lives.
真是便宜
Huh! Bargain.
我给你们一个选择
I give you a choice.
离开这颗行星 否则我会阻止你们
Leave this planet, or I'll stop you.
怎么 就凭你
What? You?
困在你的小盒子里 怎么阻止
Trapped in your box?
是的 就凭我
Yes. Me.
昨天我们刚刚见证了新世界的开端
Yesterday saw the start of a brave new world.
今天却可能见证它的终结
Today might see it end.
街上毫无人烟
The streets are deserted.
所有人都在家里 静静等待
Everyone's home, just waiting,
此时此刻 全人类的命运取决于纽约
as the future is decided in New York.
这里是纽约的午夜时分
It's midnight here in New York.
联合国召开全体大会
The United Nations has gathered.
英国已递交确凿证据
England has provided them with absolute proof
证明大规模杀伤性武器的确存在
that the massive weapons of destruction do exist.
用不了多久
The Security Council will
安理会就将作出决议
make the resolution in a matter of minutes.
一旦密码被发送
And once the codes are released,
人类的首次星际大战就将开始
humanity's first interplanetary war begins.
中士
Sergeant!
我们会在首相办公室接电话
We'll take the call in the Prime Minister's office.
坚守岗位
Maintain your positions.
祝你好运
Good luck.
看呐 这个电话真是红色的
Look at that! The telephone is actually red!
他们还有多久会来电
How long till they phone?
就快了
Counting down...
好吧 博士 我不是说我信任你
Alright, Doctor. I'm not saying I trust you,
但你一定有什么办法
but there must be something you can do.
如果我们能使葡萄酒发酵 就可以制作醋酸
If we could ferment the Port, we could make acetic acid.
米奇 有结果吗 -有不少紧急号码
Mickey, any luck? - There's loads of emergency numbers.
但都是语音信箱 -语音信箱害惨我们了
They're all on voicemail. - Voicemail dooms us all.
如果我们可以离开这里 -有一个办法
If we could just get out of here. - There's a way out.
什么 -一直都有一个办法
What? - There's always been a way out.
那我们为什么不用呢
Then why don't we use it?
因为我不能保证你女儿的安全
Because I can't guarantee your daughter will be safe.
不管是什么办法 不准你拿我女儿冒险
Don't you dare! Whatever it is, don't you dare!
这就是问题所在 如果我什么都不做
That's the thing. If I don't dare,
所有人都会死 -那就做吧
everyone dies. - Do it.
你连是什么办法都不知道 就让我做
You don't even know what it is, you'd just let me?
没错
Yeah.
求你了博士 求你
Please, Doctor, please!
她是我女儿 还是个孩子啊
She's my daughter, she's just a kid.
你以为我不清楚这点吗
Do you think I don't know that?
因为这是我的生活 杰琪
Cos this is my life, Jackie.
它并不有趣 也不潇洒
It's not fun, it's not smart.
而是不停地站出来作出决定
It's standing up and making a decision.
因为除了我就没别人了 -那你还等什么
Because nobody else will. - Then what are you waiting for?
我可以拯救了世界却要失去你
I could save the world, but lose you.
但这不是你的决定 博士 这是我的
Except it's not your decision, Doctor. It's mine.
你又到底是谁
And who the hell are you?
哈丽特·琼斯 弗莱德尔北区议员
Harriet Jones, MP for Flydale North.
在这房间里唯一一位民选代表
The only elected representative in this room.
为民所选 为民所用
Chosen by the people, for the people,
我代表民众命令你 去做吧
and on behalf of the people, I command you. Do it.
胜利
Victory...
就该这么赤裸裸
should be naked!
我们怎么出去 -不出去 就待在这
How do we get out? - We don't. We stay here.
安理会正在投票 结果随时可能出来
The Council is voting. The result should be known any second now.
使用密码Buffalo 它能覆盖所有密码
Use the Buffalo password, it overrides everything.
你在干什么
What are you doing?
黑进皇家海军
Hacking into the Royal Navy.
进去了 有了 "金牛座"号
We're in! Here it is, HMS Taurean,
特拉法加级核潜艇
Trafalgar Class submarine,
距普利茅斯海岸16公里
ten miles off the coast of Plymouth.
好 我们要选一种导弹
Right, we need to select a missile.
不能选核导弹 我们没有接入密码
We can't go nuclear. We don't have the defence codes.
不需要 普通导弹就行
We don't need it, all we need is an ordinary missile.
第一类是什么
What's the first category?
鱼叉反舰导弹 UGM-84A型
Sub harpoon, UGM-84A.
就是它 选它
That's the one! Select!
我可以阻止你
I could stop you.
那就动手吧
Do it then.
准备好了吗
Ready for this?
好了
Yeah.
笨蛋米奇 世界交给你了
Mickey the idiot, the world is in your hands.
发射
Fire!
天呐
My god!
这些钢板有多结实
How solid are these?
不够结实 只是为抵抗短程武器攻击建造的
Not solid enough. Built for short-range attack,
不能抵御这种大家伙
nothing this big.
好吧 该我做决定了
All right, I'm making a decision.
我不会坐以待毙的 我们要挺过去
I'm not gonna die. We're gonna ride this one out.
这跟地震应该是类似的
It's like what they said about earthquakes,
你可以站在门框下活下来
you can survive by standing under a doorframe.
这个壁橱很小 所以很结实
This cupboard's small, so it's strong.
快来帮忙 快
Come and help me. Come on!
投票结果出来了
The vote is in.
安理会说
The Council says...
同意
yes.
他们正在发送密码
They are releasing the codes.
电话快给我响起来
Ring, damn you!
出现在雷达上了
It's on radar!
反导代号556
Counter defence 556.
让他们停止拦截
Stop them intercepting it!
我正在做呢 -好小子
I'm doing it now! - Good boy.
代号556反导失效
556 neutralised.
"有敌情"是什么意思
What do you mean, "incoming"?
目标 唐宁街
所有人快出去 现在
Everybody out! Now! Now!
这到底怎么回事
What the hell is that for?
先生 有一枚导弹
Sir, there's a missile...
抱歉
Sorry!
那是我的 你拿成我的了
That's mine. You've got mine!
给我伪装起来 伪装起来
Disguise me, disguise me!
金发的是你的 我要另一个 快脱了
No, you're the blonde. I want the other one, take it off!
大家快跑
Everybody, run!
快跑 快离开这
Run! Let's get out of here!
很高兴认识二位
Well, nice knowing you both.
汉尼拔保佑
Hannibal!
见鬼...
Oh, bol. . .
英国制造
Made in Britain!
天呐 你们没事吧
Oh, my God. Are you all right?
我是哈丽特·琼斯 弗莱德尔北区议员
Harriet Jones, MP, Flydale North.
立即联络联合国
I want you to contact the UN immediately.
告诉各国代表危机已经解除
Tell the ambassadors the crisis is over,
他们不用出动了 别愣着 快去告诉大家
they can step down. Go on, tell the news!
遵命 -这烂摊子够忙活一阵子的了
Yes, ma'am. - Someone's got a hell of a job sorting this lot out.
天呐 我们连首相都没有
Oh, Lord! We haven't even got a Prime Minister!
或许你可以试试
Maybe you should have a go.
我 我只是个后座议员
Me! I'm only a backbencher.
我愿意投你一票 -别说笑了
I'd vote for ya. - Now, don't be silly.
我最好去看看能帮上什么忙
Look, I'd better go and see if I can help.
等等我
Hang on!
我们安全了 地球安全了
We're safe, the Earth is safe!
中士
Sergeant!
我就说我好像听过她的名字
I thought I knew the name.
哈丽特·琼斯
Harriet Jones.
未来的首相 连任三届
Future Prime Minister, elected for three successive terms.
英国黄金时代的缔造者
The architect of Britain's Golden Age.
危机过去了
The crisis has passed!
女士们先生们 我要对你们说
Ladies and gentlemen, I have something to say to you all. . .
今天
Here today. . .
人类屹立不倒
Mankind stands tall -
坚不可摧
proud and undefeated!
上帝保佑人类
God bless the human race.
人类屹立不倒
Mankind stands tall. . .
这个哈丽特·琼斯以为自己是谁
Harriet Jones - who does she think she is?
你看她 把功劳都揽到自己身上
Look at her, taking all the credit.
被采访应该是你
It should be you on there.
是我女儿拯救了世界 -博士也帮了点忙
My daughter saved the world! - I think the Doctor helped a bit.
好吧 算他一个
All right, then, him too.
应该封你们个爵位什么的
You should be given knighthoods.
那不是他的风格
It's not the way he does things.
干净利落 来去匆匆
No fuss, he just moves on.
如果你了解了解他 就不会觉得他是坏人了
He's not that bad, if you gave him a chance.
他倒是挺擅长解决危机
He's good in a crisis, I'll give him that.
世界真是不一样了
Oh-h-h! The world has changed.
你都开始夸他了 -不然还能说什么
You're saying nice things about him. - Well, I've no choice.
你已经迷上他了 肯定是甩不掉了
There's no getting rid of him, since you're infatuated.
我才没迷上他
I'm not infatuated!
他喜欢吃什么 -问这个干什么
What does he eat? - How d'you mean?
不如我做个土豆牛肉派
I was gonna do shepherd's pie.
我们一家人正式见个面
All of us, proper sit-down.
因为
Cos. . .
我想听听
I'm ready to listen.
我想了解你和你的生活方式
I wanna learn about you and him and that life you lead.
但他可是外星人
Only, I dunno, he's an alien.
据我所知他们吃的都是草 别针什么的
For all I know he eats grass and safety pins and things.
他能吃土豆牛肉派
He'll have shepherds pie...
你要给他做饭吗 -不行吗
You're gonna cook for him? - What's wrong with that?
他终于找到个做菜一样难吃的了
He's finally met his match.
别逼我扇你 丫头片子
You're not too old for a slap, you know!
我们明天可以去找你外婆
We can go and visit your gran tomorrow.
学点法国菜
Better learn some French.
我告诉过她你去过法国
I told her you were in France.
还说你在找男朋友
I said you were au-pairing. . .
塔迪斯来电
喂
Hello?
等我几个小时
Right, I'll be a couple of hours,
我们就可以出发了 -你居然有电话
then we can go. - You've got a phone!
我都能穿越时空
You think I can travel through space and time
可能没有电话吗 等我几个小时
and I haven't got a phone? Like I said, couple of hours.
我只需要发个屏蔽信号
I've just got to send a dispersal...
好了 这样就能屏蔽斯利辛的广告
There you go, that's cancelling out the Slitheens' advert
免得再有哪个投机商跑来地球闹事
in case any bargains hunters turn up.
我妈妈在做饭
Um, my mother's cooking.
很好 记得小火慢炖 让她入入味儿
Good, put her on a slow heat and let her simmer.
她在泡茶 给我俩喝的 -我不喝茶
She's cooking tea. For us. - I don't do that.
她想了解你 -真不巧
She wants to get to know you. - Tough,
我有比喝茶更重要的事
I've better things to do.
喝杯茶而已 -对我可没这么简单
- It's just tea. - Not to me, it isn't.
她是我妈 -又不是我妈
She's my mother. - Well, she's not mine.
这叫什么话 -你也可以留在家里
That's not fair. - Well, you can stay there if you want.
但马头星云就要发生等离子风暴了
But right now there's this plasma storm brewing in the Horsehead Nebula.
燎天大火 烧遍一千万英里
Fires are burning, ten million miles wide.
我可以把塔迪斯开进风暴中心
I could fly the Tardis right into the heart of it
然后借着冲击波一路飞出来
then ride the shockwave all the way out,
划过天际 随心所欲
hurtle right across the sky and end up anywhere.
你自己选
Your choice.
洛斯 我在想
Rose? I was thinking,
我这有一瓶新年时留下的杏仁甜酒
I've got that bottle of Amaretto from New Year's Eve.
他喝酒吗
Does he drink?
我在问他喝不喝酒 -他喝
I was wondering whether he drinks or not. - Yeah, he does.
别走 宝贝
Don't go, sweetheart.
求你别走
Please don't go.
这才对 再敢乱画看我怎么收拾你 走吧
Good lad. Graffiti that again and I'll 'ave ya. Now, beat it.
我刚去了趟商店
I just went down the shop.
我就在想 这个世界从此不同了
And I was thinking, y'know, like, the whole world's changed.
外星人 飞船公然地出现
Aliens and spaceships all in public.
结果却是这个
And here it is.
外星人骗局
他们怎么能这么想
How can they do that?
他们亲眼看见了啊 -你们还没准备好
They saw it! - You're just not ready.
你们乐于相信一个看不见的东西
You're happy to believe in something that's invisible,
但如果它真的出现在面前 你们就
but if it's staring you in the face,
"看不见 就是看不见"
"Nope, Can't see it!"
这个特点是有科学的解释的 因为你们笨
There's a scientific explanation for that - you're thick.
我们都是笨蛋
We're just idiots.
也有聪明的 -是吗
Well, not all of you. - Yeah?
给你个礼物 米奇
Present for you, Mickey.
这有个病毒 把它传到网上
That's a virus. Put it online,
它会销毁所有与我有关的消息
it'll destroy every mention of me.
我就不复存在了
I'll cease to exist.
为什么要那么做 -因为你说的没错
What d'you wanna do that for? - Cos you're right.
我很危险 我不希望有人追踪到我
I am dangerous. I don't want anybody following me.
你怎么能一边说这种话一边带她走
How can you say that, and then take her with you?
你可以跟我一起走 照顾她
You could look after her. Come with us.
不行
I can't.
你的这种生活
This life of yours...
太不一样 我接受不了
it's just too much, I couldn't do it.
别告诉她我这么说
Don't tell her I said that.
我会找个正经工作 周末兼职 通过考试
I'll get a proper job. I'll work weekends, I'll pass my test.
如果吉姆再来找我 我会拒绝他
If Jim comes round again, I'll say no,
真的 -我不是因为你才走的
I really will. - I'm not leaving cos of you.
我只是去旅行而已
I'm travelling, that's all,
我还会回来的 -但不安全
and then I'll come back. - But it's not safe.
妈 如果你见过外面的世界
Mum. If you saw it out there,
你也不会想留在家里的
you'd never stay home.
东西挺多啊 -我第一次
Got enough stuff. - The first time
走进塔迪斯时是临时起意
I stepped in there, it was spur-of-the-moment.
现在我要常驻了 你甩不掉我了
Now I'm signing up. You're stuck with me.
跟我们一起走吧 地方很大的
Come with us. There's plenty of room.
不行 他是个累赘 我不会带他走的
No chance. He's a liability, I'm not having him on board.
这次多亏他我们才活下来的
We'd be dead without him.
我已经决定了
My decision is final.
抱歉
Sorry.
祝你好运
Good luck, yeah?
你还是没法向我保证 如果她走丢了呢
You still can't promise me. What if she gets lost?
如果你出了事 博士
What if something happens to you, Doctor,
丢下她孤身一人 迷失在某个
and she's left all alone, standing on some
几百万光年外的星球上 你要我等多久
moon a million light years away? How long do I wait then?
妈 你忘了 这是台时间机器
Mum, you're forgetting, it's a time machine.
我可以走遍各个星球
I could traveling round suns and planets
哪怕一直走到宇宙的边缘
and all the way out to the edge of the universe,
等我回到这里
and by the time I get back, yeah,
可能只过去了十秒钟 就十秒
ten seconds would've passed. Just ten seconds.
你就别担心了
So stop worrying.
十秒钟后我就回来了 好吗
I'll see you in ten seconds' time, yeah?
十秒过了
Ten seconds.
真是个壮观的博物馆 -是个外星博物馆
It's a great big museum. An alien museum.
下集预告
看来有人对此兴趣浓厚啊
Someone's got a hobby.
那个笼子里是我唯一的活物收藏品
The cage contains my one living specimen.
它肯定是穿越了时空 唯一的幸存者
It must've fallen through time, the only survivor.
他会死的 快帮帮他
It's killing him. Do something!
我发誓 这个基地里无人安全
I swear no-one on this base is safe.
你们得把它关在那里
You've gotta keep it in that cell.
它出不来 那个锁有数十亿种密码组合
It can't get out. That lock's got a billion combinations. . .
他们是平民 放行
Civilians, let 'em through!
它会杀光我们的
That thing is gonna kill every last one of us!
最近的城镇在哪 -盐湖城
Where's the nearest town? - Salt Lake City.
人口 -一百万
Population? - One million.
他们死定了
All dead.
如果你想要命令 那就给你一个
If you want orders, follow this one.
你怎么不去死
Why don't you just die?!
我们马上就到了 再拖两秒
We're nearly there! Give us two seconds.
我是来帮忙的 我是博士
I've come to help. I'm The Doctor.
消灭
Exterminate!
不可能 -消灭
Impossible. - Exterminate!